Andrea Cavalcanti

Cell phone: (647) 917-6207 Toronto-ON andreacnas@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/andrea-cavalcanti/

lin.com/in/andrea-cavalcanti/ github.com/Andreacnas

2022 - Graduation date on 04/2023

PROFILE

I am a tech professional with an engineering and programming background. I have vast experience in industries such as Startup, E-commerce, Logistics, Education, Management Consulting, Finance and Health sectors. I am also savvy about Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), JavaScript (jQuery), C#.Net, Java, HTML, CSS, SQL, Python, and I have knowledge of Agile Methodologies (Scrum Master certified). Furthermore, I consider myself a fast learner who is a team player plus works collaboratively and successfully with others, as well as I can communicate effectively with all organizational levels.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• Languages: HTML5, XML, CSS3, JavaScript, C#.Net, Java, Python;

• Diploma Software Engineering Technician - Centennial College

- Databases: SQL Server and Oracle SQL;
- Frameworks/Others: GitHub, REST APIs, JSON, jQuery, Ajax, Operating Systems (Unix/Linux).

EDUCATION

Diploma Software Engineering Technician Centennia Conege 202.	2 Graduation date on 04/2023
College Credits Information Technology Solutions – Humber College	2022- 2022
• Postgraduate Occupational Safety Engineering – Pontificia Universidade Catoli	ica de MG 2014 - 2016
• BA Industrial Engineering – Centro Universitario UniFBV	2008 - 2013
Certificate - Professional Scrum Master I (PSM I) Scrum.org	#963324

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

- Designed and created an artist website using JavaScript, HTML and CSS as a team;
- Developed a web application using ¡Query and website API;
- Created JDBC GUI applications to connect to a data source, send queries and update statements, and retrieve results received from the database using Java as a team;
- Designed a customer management system with CRUD operations using C# and .NET framework, and SQL Server;
- Created various menu-driven programs using data structures and design patterns strategies.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Logistics/Customer Care Coordinator Silk & Snow | Canada

12/2019 - 11/2020

- Created, implemented and analyzed performance KPIs;
- Edited and updated new features on WooCommerce;
- Ensured all outbound/inbound shipments were processed and shipped as outlined in KPIs;
- Worked cross-functionally with all internal departments (Accounting, Customer Service, IT) and external stakeholders to solve problems related to logistics for all modes of transportation;
- Supported inventory control, including monthly cycle count reconciliation, order forecasting, coordinating and communicating shipment activities;
- Reconciled logistics reverse charges.

Andrea Cavalcanti

Cell phone: (647) 917-6207 Toronto-ON

andreacnas@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/andrea-cavalcanti/ github.com/Andreacnas

Sales and Service Representative GoodLife Fitness | Canada

08/2019 - 12/2019

- Achieved 100% of monthly goals that include sale of membership, booking appointments and generating leads:
- Built relationships using strong communication skills and the ability to help and assist others;
- Participated in daily management meetings to evaluate club statistics to improve sales.

Finance Coordinator 09/2014 – 03/2019

Kumon | Brazil

- Handled a variety of duties related to coordination of business activities;
- Maintained business documentation, contacts, client files, contracts and correspondence;
- Updated and filed system regards financial expenses and invoices using Excel;
- Provided supervision, motivation, and interaction with students to assist them in achieving their full potential.

Business Valuation Consultant

07/2011 - 08/2014

Ernst & Young (EY) | Brazil

- Performed comprehensive financial statement analysis and created/maintained financial models of existing private equity investments;
- Conducted company's valuation analysis, including comparable company, precedent transaction, discounted cash flow, and other valuation methodologies or metrics;
- Executed market research, consumer trends and competitors to better design effective scenarios;
- Reviewed and analyzed client provided information to conduct an depth analysis of financial and operational results;
- Assisted physical inventory audits at multiple plants.

LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent)
- Portuguese (Native)
- Spanish (Basic)